remember last episode where i filled the
village full of villagers again i
repopulated it myself with hours of work
yeah
well
they've all disappeared again i don't
know what's going on
but there's no mobs here i spent ages
lighting this up
but all the villagers have gone
again well hello everyone welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft and
welcome back to well not so greenville
anymore this is i guess it's relegated
back to hermitville ah
maybe that has something to do with it
why on earth oh
did they see me look nobody's triggered
a raid there's no raid above
the thing they're just standing there as
well it's really creepy oh yeah look
i've got my zoom function back as well
um i might ask doc what's going on we
built this wall or wren built this wall
all around the village
so that we didn't have this problem
anymore the doc's coming to have a look
now look over there
yeah
what do we do
let's burn them when you said burn them
i thought you meant just
you know kill them you actually mean
burn them yeah
if we burn him you know that doesn't
kill as a account as a play but watch
out there's a johnny with him so we can
kill all of him but the flag guy we
gotta burn all right okay so just the
flag
they're on me yes
they're not even moving yeah they're
looking at me i think
yeah
look at you guys
oh god
this is the stupidest thing so yeah this
is not safe man like this will never be
safe all the villagers are gone again
yeah
tell me about it
it's like ah it's a never-ending
never-ending cycle so but yeah we gotta
watch out but yeah if you see something
just
no no no no no now that's not on
that dude look look
what the what is going on
there's like a fake raid i swear
dude that's not okay
um
it's right here right
he's locked again he's coming for you
don't hit him
i'm not oh okay i'm right i'm trying to
go for it okay he's dead he's dead we
will never have a village population
here yeah
the village will never be safe okay so
now we wait two seconds to see if they
spawn somewhere else now they're
they're here man
where where where what are they doing i
think we figured out why the village
is always empty it doesn't look like
another patrol has spawned but that
could very well be why the village is so
empty
this is not great guys because
i put a lot of effort into repopulating
this place and it's all for nothing it
turns out
i'm not going to spend more time
breeding them on camera i think that if
i'm going to repopulate the village for
a second time i'm going to do it just
off camera however i am going to place
lots of iron golems around because i
think that these guys are probably our
best bet at actually trying to protect
the village
i think that these guys are definitely
the best way to defend the village but i
need to be careful because too many of
these will cause a spot of lag so
just got to be careful
right there's officially more golems
than villagers now which is totally
backwards
but hopefully this will definitely help
the great thing about hermitcraft is
that we have unlimited iron and farms
for everything so we don't have to worry
about all the resources we're spending
on this right hopefully that's enough
golems around
there's um
not even anything to protect at the
moment but it's good to have some life
in the village now i don't know if
you've noticed but mumbo has been
building his house
in the village
and i can't help but notice
it's exactly
one block taller
than my house
that cannot be a coincidence
he has got to be trying to build the
biggest house and i'll tell you what
mumbo jumbo i won't let you i won't i
won't stand for it i haven't even
finished my house and now i'm gonna have
to make it bigger i'm glad that i didn't
finish it because i'm gonna have to
build a bit more i have been doing some
really nice progress on this but
you forced my hand mumbo jumbo look at
it it is exactly one block taller than
my base
that is totally unacceptable so tell you
what we're gonna make this substantially
taller than mumbo's house and we'll show
him who is the ruler of the sahara
street house project i'll tell you what
mumbo jumbo i'm just kidding mumbo we
love you really
but you can't have the biggest house i'm
afraid thankfully i moved all of my
stuff in oh
thankfully i moved all of my stuff over
here uh we didn't see anything uh wasn't
i don't know how that got there it
wasn't wasn't my
things so that i can actually do quite a
lot of work without having to go
backwards and forwards from the base one
of the most important things that i've
got with me is all of these stacks of
log now why are all the iron golems
hanging out there
you're not gonna defend anything by
standing there oh no
no he didn't
he just saw that my i'm making this
slightly bigger
this this no this is beyond coincidence
he saw that the chimney was
just above his and then he decided to
make a giant antenna i see i see you
mumbo jumbo i know what you're playing
at i know these games oh it's about to
go down this is a build off
this is this is happening i mean there's
quite an easy test to see if this is
and that is
let's see how he responds
when i create a slightly bigger house
it's coming along nicely it's looking
more rickety than ever but it's still
not quite as tall as mumbo's yet he's
just built that antenna just to make my
life a little bit harder but don't you
worry the detail is going to come later
but the shape of this house is looking
fantastic i need to take this to the
next level
literally the next level now hopefully
this tower here
will set the record because i'm already
above that antenna there
and i don't think mumbo really stands a
chance
unless he wants to add a few more layers
to that build so i'm feeling pretty
confident about this and i gotta say
despite this being not particularly
detailed the shape of this house is
absolutely incredible
look at this it started off with a
normal villager house and it's just
extended and extended and extended
unfortunately for me i'm very quickly
running out of spruce wood and i think
the key to this particular type of build
that i'm doing this sort of weird
higgledy piggledy kind of held together
by rope and bubblegum or whatever it
needs to not have too many flat surfaces
so you see i had like this big chunk of
spruce going here and i've decided to
put another layer on here the problem is
every time you overlap you kind of have
to go a bit taller so at some point this
does have to end i'm just not entirely
sure where but the main thing is that my
house is officially taller it's official
i have run out of spruce wood but i
think that we've made some very very
decent progress on this from every angle
this house looks like a total
mess it's amazing i absolutely love it i
need to extend this chimney all the way
up but
look at this we've got the tallest
street we've got the tallest building in
the whole village
which is absolutely amazing i really
like how this is coming along i could
even do a tutorial on this one day i'm
not sure if this is something that
people would be interested in doing
but i just love this style it's kind of
all over the place an organized mess
just like me it's definitely got a lot
more work to do but i am loving the
direction that this is going
so that is where i'm gonna have to leave
this cause i'm gonna have to deforest
all that spruce over there in order to
get the materials i need to continue
this or i could just go and give ren
some more diamonds so i've done my best
to tidy up the area around here
and i think that and i think that we can
expect the villages to improve over time
there's a book on here
oh
dear hermit
oh dear hermit if you are reading this
you have been selected for an epic quest
your goal should you choose to accept it
is nothing short of saving the world
to begin your journey go to 7800-550
that's all i can say for now
well
a villager didn't leave that there i'm
not even sure why i broke that it's just
in the middle of the road someone's
clearly left this note hoping that
either i or someone on sahara street is
going to find it the question is do we
take the very obvious bait
when someone tells you to go to
coordinates that's
never exactly a good sign oh all right
let's go seven thousand
eight hundred
seven thousand eight hundred so
this way and so it should be straight
over there oh it's not far at all we're
nearly there in fact
so
that's -550 800 should be just around
here
800 oh g g you've been had
jingled
because i'm a good guy i don't want
anyone else to be jingled i'm going to
get rid of that
i'm going to go over here
this is the most embarrassing thing
that's ever happened to me in
hermitcraft
and i'm going to burn this book for the
sake of everyone on this server i don't
want anyone else to get jingled
public service done
oh my god i can't believe we got jingled
really
i thought the jingler was gone i think
that's about all we can do here in the
114 village
so what i'm going to do now
is head back over to the mainlands
first things first we should check if
anybody has done my electric course
which i've actually been working on like
a little elytra symbol around the back
of but it's not actually been go very
well i need to work on this seriously
because this thing is like removing the
gap there so it just looks like a big
grey blob don't worry i'm gonna fix that
so it looks like the only person to try
is false and she got 2 minutes and 19
seconds that is 40 seconds longer than
mine that is that's not the best score
in the world folks see i'm afraid but it
looks like four attempts and
eight diamonds
this
is brilliant i'm gonna leave that in
there i want to know how many diamonds i
make in total from this over time i just
hope that a few more people will play
the course i also added this feel free
to fly around and learn the course
obviously i don't want people just uh
doing lots of test runs because they
should be paying but if they want to
learn the course and they go right i've
got to go through there then that one
and then over here you get the idea so
they they learn the course
uh first that's completely fine because
this is a really complicated course
and i
wouldn't expect anyone to know where to
go first time i bet false's score got
better and better and better as she just
remembered where all of the rings were
but the main reason that i came over
here is because sahara has had a bit of
a finale going on basically mumbo and
iskall went and did some
finalizing redstone i believe and
i didn't really want to go over the
technical stuff because i don't really
understand how it works but they said
they left me a tech report there we go
tech report by mumbo jumbo to the head
honcho ceo i don't need to know how the
product works it just needs to work and
make money so let's go into the office
here
oh yeah all the parrots are gone i
forgot that all the parrots had gone i'm
gonna have to replace those as well
anyway so let's take a look so they went
over all of this which i'll be honest
i don't know how it works and i'll i'll
be guessing that a lot of you don't know
how this works
um so i think we're pretty much in the
same boat so let's take a look at what
they've written tech report random
explosion occurred upon activation we
assume this is just cobwebs being blown
out of the redstone
random explosions when it's turned do
you know what should we go and test this
out because i'm pretty sure that sahara
actually functions now so we should be
able to order something that's not a
good sign that they've been around the
back
don't know what this button does
that doesn't look like it's reset well
let's just give it a go shall we so i
believe what we do oh there's nothing in
here yeah it looks like we definitely
can't test it because it doesn't look
testable
at all oh let's have another read then
need to separate the receipt from the
orders need to stop item spillage in the
oh okay final report conclusion sahara
is now brilliant completion timeline is
now very much near-ish
ish
so that means sahara is very close to
being finished oh i saw that flash is
that a good thing or a bad thing what
happens if i throw something in here it
doesn't
doesn't know what oh is it going to
bring me potatoes
i'm guessing that this doesn't work and
that i maybe shouldn't have thrown
potatoes in it
i'm pretty sure it shouldn't be bringing
me items i've clogged up the system with
potatoes and it's officially bringing me
items because each one of these means
something this means like order received
then it looks for the module and then it
brings it oh so it might get stuck here
because it won't be able to find the
module so i'll be very surprised if it
lights up the third one
yep it looks like i'm safe um nobody
tell mumbo or iskall that i threw
potatoes in the very complicated very
expensive machine that we've been
investing in for the last i don't know
three months don't tell them that i
threw potatoes in it but do you know
what this means this means that we can
plan
the grand opening of sahara and it looks
so much better with optifine without all
of the grid pattern on the glass it
looks magnificent so we need to do or
plan
some fantastic opening for this
i have no idea what that's going to be i
think i need to think about this for a
second of course we've got to have a big
red ribbon that we cut we need to invite
some of our friends from the hermitcraft
community and we need to
we need to sell some sand that's the
main thing we could do oh we could do a
big discount on the first day and maybe
some hermit news could be there this
could be fantastic
i guess this means that like
i i can boss those guys around and get
them to do the redstone and stuff so i
can be like i want pictures of
spider-man on my desk by morning kind of
thing kind of thing i'm the ceo now of
sahara industries i don't really know
how the machine works but one of the
things that i definitely need to do is
organize a grand opening maybe even in
the next episode or the one after that i
don't want to make any promises but i'm
going to start organizing something
really epic for the grand opening of
sahara
i think the problem is we're only going
to sell sand so i hope all of the
customers really like some sand
now there's one other thing that has
been going on in the background and it's
actually to do with mumbo jumbo leo
and it's not really that great as some
of you may know he had some issues with
his intro and he had to get rid of the
song that he's been he had to get rid of
the song that he's been using for years
so i thought i'd help out my old buddy
old pal and i'd ask not me no not me not
me i can't i can't sing but someone that
i know
to come along and sing us a mumbo jumbo
intro fresh out of the packet ready for
him to enjoy so
i'll uh i don't think she needs any
introductions let's just uh let's just
uh hand over the mic so to speak
mumbo jumbo mumbo jumbie bum
mumbo jumbo playing on hermitcraft
voice of an angel i'm telling you voice
of an angel
it's a miracle
as i was saying it's a miracle that we
managed to secure such a high-profile
singer with such an amazing voice who
definitely doesn't have a cold right now
i can't i don't know if you could tell
but my
my nasals have been all over the place
hopefully mumbo likes his new intro that
we made for him
i've actually got a version with a bit
of music as well let's see if it sort of
fits together
mumbo jumbo mumbo
jumbo jumbo playing on hermitcraft
uh it kind of works i think he should
use it once just as a joke
anyway
there's actually something else that i
really wanted to show you guys it's not
super important but
it's something to do with 1.14
and i don't know if it's going to be
possible or if it's going to be fixed in
the later versions but i thought i'd
show you anyway so unfortunately i trade
has been uh well
evacuated shall we say some of them
survived but most of them didn't and i
think impulse is actually working on
getting everything up to scratch right
but it turns out in 114
that armor
can have as many enchantments as you
like so i spent about an hour yesterday
putting
all of them
on so i've got protection respiration
unbreaking aqua affinity mending
projectile protection blast protection
and fire protection
honestly
this is op god armor this shouldn't be
possible normally there's a limit to
what you can put on some some
enchantments don't mix very well but
the g legs the g boots and the g hat we
don't care this is god armour now i'm
definitely not going to be putting those
in the did you die boxes it's just not
happening it's just not happening i'm
afraid it took me so long just to get
all these done it took me so long to get
the digi die boxes done anyway but it's
a good start and maybe someone should
capitalize on making like a god armor
shop or something like that a place
where you couldn't do it so i imagine
the impulse
will be providing that service
when
he gets all of his villages sorted out
which is super exciting because this was
very expensive to do but
well worth it in my opinion in light of
sahara being nearly ready i think we
should make a sort of a big
grand opening ribbon to indicate to
everybody
that it is on its way so if we do
something like this just to kind of
cover it up
and then what we'll do is we'll try and
make a bow out of red wool to show that
it's sort of ready but
making a bow in a small area it's never
gone well for me let's let's put it that
way so let's give it a go
but like i said this may not look like a
ribbon or a bow at all
you see what i mean it just ah that
looks like a total mess okay round two
let's try this again
that's certainly a start and then if we
actually have sort of the ribbons come
down like this
and we show that it's uh
there we go that kind of that kind of
works we might not need as long as that
but there we go that kind of works it's
uh like i said not the best but making
ribbon is is difficult but then all we
need to do is add the sign on the front
saying
grand opening coming
soon
there we go the red ribbons that you
know what that actually doesn't look too
bad at all i can tell what it is or
maybe i just know what it is because i
made it but hopefully that will get some
attention and maybe we can actually well
it's actually going to be really
anti-climactic isn't it because to get
rid of it you're going to have to get
like a pair of shears and individually
break all of them or maybe you know
mumbo and iskall can help me and we'll
all break it together and it'll be
magnificent and sahara will be open and
we might make um
a couple of diamonds a couple of
diamonds
oh no
that is so unfair i stood no chance at
all i just got out the other side of the
portal and ah
that is awful
the creeper must have walked into the
portal and waited for me out the other
side
well
better go repair that later on
but now i'm gonna head back to the 114
hermitville because i've got some
villagers to make again
the problem is i've only got one
villager somehow i've lost villagers
even in my laboratory
hello there whoa
what is there a fox doing here there's
animals going through portals left right
and center
glad to see all the iron golems are
being useful again at least we've still
got you village agreeing but down here
it's uh not looking so healthy so we may
have to borrow you again
to repopulate the village for the second
time
so as you can see down here
no one survived there's nine golem still
but we've only got one villager and i'm
not even gonna mess around with that
nonsense anymore i'm gonna go straight
to here
and uh hopefully get this village
repopulated again
but my goodness if it keeps going like
that i don't know what to do
now i don't know what to do but i'm
afraid that is all i have time for to in
today's episode might be a little bit of
a shorter episode but there was a lot to
be done and i've got a lot of work to do
especially on my house
you know trying to get out of here is
the worst so i think my next task is to
go ahead and detail a lot of this house
and maybe even finish most of it off but
like i said run out of spruce wood it's
such a pain to have to go back to the
old lands to the new lands so it might
actually be a lot quicker if i just
deforest a lot of this and then i'm
going to use all this on my new tower
house it needs a name or something and
we need to make sure well we just need
to establish
the dominance
on sahara street
anyway thank you very much for watching
and i'll see you in the next episode
good bye
please subscribe to my second channel
because i want a hundred thousand
subscribers
thank you
you